[music]
>> Oh, well, hello.
Welcome to the channel. Didn't see you
there. Hey, glad that you are here.
If you're not sure who I am, I'm
Fiddling Johnny. This is my fiddle
channel and magic product review. And I
don't want to waste any of your time
because I'm going to do a
one of the harshest rants and reviews of
the year on pen
through coin. Yep.
It's going to be a rough one today. So,
stick around.
We'll get right into it. I'll throw up a
quick demo so you can see demo, and then
we'll talk about uh what really pissed
me off about this release.
Stick around. Get right into it.
All right, this is attempt two. Maybe
I'll show a blooper reel if this goes
well enough cuz on the first attempt I
dropped the coin. Classic. All right,
let's do a quick demo for you of uh
pen through coin. I I I want to point
out I'm going to try to get as close as
possible so you can see the coin. You
can show your coin
both sides. Totally fine.
Put that down for a second.
Pen, basically a a normal pen. Um
and I want to do this as
close-up
as possible so you can
see that everything is going to stay
in focus for you. So, let's go ahead and
show both sides for you there. Um
let's go ahead and do
the actual penetration. I'll try to do
it as close as possible, maybe more so
than what would be in real life with a
real person, but
somewhere right there in the middle
is the actual soft spot.
You can already see
that it has penetrated
that coin.
We'll do it a little bit further.
And historically,
you'd only show the front side, the nice
side of that.
But this is you can actually show
both sides. So, I think that's a real
advantage.
Uh with this, you can have your
spectator
play with it, moving it up and down.
If they would like, I think one of the
things that some people complain about,
but you can actually see how the metal
from the back side, if you look really
close. Now, most spectators aren't going
to be this close, but you can actually
see how the metal has penetrated um
through there. So, at the end, I just
wanted you to see this all the way to
the end.
You can see that we've got it all the
way to the edge, and I want you
to be able to examine it and see that
like it all happens in just seconds,
and goes back to its normal self. You
can now hand out both pen
and quarter
for full examination.
I hope that helps.
Okay, I do not want to waste a moment. I
want to get into my little rant here
about pissed off about.
But I figure if I'm going to do that,
it's time to retire something.
This hat This This hat
used to see during the summer months.
It's kind of getting yeah.
Oh, so it's time
to bring in a brand new.
It's twin uh
brand spanking new. We're going to
retire this one. Maybe we'll send it to
the Smithsonian
um or something like that.
Like they'll want it. All right, here we
go. Brand new hat. I hope you enjoy it.
Let's get into this review.
And I'm not going to hold back. Um
I tend to be pretty nice in these. I
tend to uh
give latitude at times, and not today.
It I
I'm undeserving of it.
What is
Pen Through Coin by Michael Ammar and
Penguin Magic? Let me begin by saying
I learned this effect from Michael Ammar
30 years ago at least, maybe a little
bit longer. I went to a lecture of his
uh at least three decades ago. Purchased
from him a VCR tape.
And it was on his VCR tape. I think at
the time he said to me that there was a
transition to more DVDs, and I think he
said to me like, "I think this is the
last VCR tape that I have." So, um
yeah. So, I watched that. It had uh Pen
Through Coin or Cigarette Through Coin.
And it was beautiful. And what was most
beautiful about it was how he ends it.
He does a switch that is so seamless
that you believe your eyes have never
left seeing that coin with the hole in
it. And as he passes it right back to
you,
the whole vanish is done. Um and it was
done with such elegance. I've been
inspired by it ever since to try to
replicate in the beautiful way that he
does.
I have performed uh Cigarette Through
Coin not hundreds of times, literally
thousands of times. So, this is an
effect I'm really well aware of. Uh have
performed professionally
thousands of times.
Now, I used to perform it with frequency
um again decades ago when I played bands
and during intermissions, I would do
magic. And since in those days people
could smoke in bars, it was a great I
would borrow somebody's cigarette,
borrow a coin, and the next thing I'm
putting the cigarette through the coin.
These days,
nobody's smoking bars anymore. In fact,
very few people smoke. Thank goodness. I
love that uh about it. So, finding the
new updated ways to do it with a uh pen
or pencil through the coin. So,
that's the effect. It's a penetration
effect, a solid through solid, which in
magic is literally one of my favorite
effects. Any penetration effect, I'm
going to check it out and be very
interested in it. And this is one I've
loved forever.
Michael Moran's now updated it. He's
updated over the years through his
different methods. I do think this is an
advancement, and I think it's a good
advancement. And the simple advantage is
that you can now show the coin cleanly
on both sides during the penetration.
It's a nice advancement.
All right, so
let's first talk about what you get, and
then I'm not going to make you wait till
the end. I'm going to rank here towards
the top.
What do you get? You're going to get one
normal quarter.
You're going to get one gimmick quarter.
Then you're going to get a consumable.
They advertise it as 100 consumables in
the package. I think they got 105. So,
basically you get 100 consumables
that you use one each time you perform.
And on top of that, since it's produced
by Penguin Magic on their video
streaming platform, you'll get a
17-minute video
that's streamable and downloadable from
Penguin Magic. 17 minutes. All right, so
let's talk about how are the
instructions?
Horrible.
Maybe some of the worst I've ever seen.
It's clearly the worst of 2026.
Just
going to curse. I promised not to curse
on this channel.
Um yeah, it's just horrible, plain and
simple. Um
and why is it horrible?
Here's the reason it's horrible.
And I'm not talking about the effect,
I'm talking about their tutorial.
Penguin Magic is responsible for this in
my opinion, not Michael.
I've experienced over buying lots of
magic tricks over the decades is that
you get a legend uh who's releasing
something and then they teach it and
they perform it. And you can see they
are great performers. They are a great
creator, but maybe not always the best
teacher. I don't think Michael Ammar
actually is a terrible teacher. He's
really probably one of the very first
for, you know, folks in our modern age
doing
um touring and and lectures and whatnot.
He's really led the way.
But I think he makes assumptions that
you know more, you know, teaches in a
way that as if you're already
experienced. And probably many of you
are already experienced, so it's not a
big deal.
But Penguin Magic's target audience is
predominantly a hobbyist and a beginner.
And I think more so for beginners here,
if you are a beginner in magic, you're
new to this effect,
they won't teach you appropriately on
this. You will end up having to teach
yourself. Now, I'm finally like you
don't need to be hand-held through
everything, but when your audience
is predominantly beginners and a
hobbyist and you disrespect them by not
teaching them the most important thing,
which is the slides on this,
you haven't done your job. You're
ripping people off.
Um and I want to be harsh because it's
true. Penguin, your audience are a lot
of young folks just learning. And the
slides that are taught on this is 17
minutes in length.
I found myself being so pissed off when
I was watching it when they went to the
slides cuz my experience I've been doing
this uh um variations of this for
decades. And basically we're just
talking switches. You can do any switch
in the world that you want and it's
totally fine. They teach three switches
on here over the course of 17 minutes.
With three switches, the total screen
time in teaching those switches is 4
minutes. All right? Um Penguin can
dispute me on that. They can type in oh
no he's been doing this for like what
are you talking about? You're not
demoing showing us.
4 freaking minutes.
To teach the slides. If you're brand new
in magic, you're not going to
can you figure it out? Yes, of course
you can figure it out. You're not dumb
dumbs, right?
But uh
I feel like Penguin Magic just messes up
on this one. It messes up on this one.
It's that
take your time. Slow down.
You're really doing a disservice to your
own brand. If I were brand new in magic
and I had purchased this, I'd be mad as
hell.
Because I would have to go to somebody
who's my mentor, somebody else who's
been doing magic for a while. Just
probably walk me through it. Or I'd
spend more hours than maybe necessary
and wasted practice time. And not good
quality practice time because I didn't
get good quality tutorial on it.
So
Penguin Magic and Eric Chien, I hope
you're listening.
I buy so much stuff from you guys.
Great respect for you Eric and your
skill level.
But you have to do a better job when you
think about your core audience on this
and you need to do more detail for the
beginner for these specific slides. Even
though they're simple slides, you did
not spend adequate time on it.
If you purchase this and you're brand
new, leave your thoughts on it. Maybe
I'm totally wrong. Maybe I've been doing
this for too many decades and have
misperception of what the new person
experiences.
But I think I'm speaking from my own
experience of like when I was younger
and starting and this was the tutorial I
got, I'd be pissed off and feel like I
got ripped off on the most important
piece of it which is what are the
methods and how do I do it?
Show you're going to get gimmicks, and
the gimmicks are great.
But, I need appropriate tutorial.
All right. 4 minutes,
three slides, all taught
too quickly and not with enough detail.
All right, let me try to be a little bit
more chipper now.
How is the gimmick?
The gimmick is pretty meaningful.
Uh and there's two aspects of this
gimmick. You're going to get a gimmick
coin. Now, the gimmick coin, the nice
thing about it is it it'll last forever.
You can drop it, throw it in the wash.
There's no moving parts. There's nothing
to break on it. So, that is nice. Many
of you who do coin magic probably
already have
this type of a gimmick coin.
The thing that is really nice is the
next evolution of this effect that
Michael
Michael Ammar has come up with.
And um
that's the consumable piece of it. So,
you're looking at it right now. It is
really freaking So, I'll pick it up to
the camera so you can see it up close.
I'll talk a little bit more about it.
All right, here it is right here. You're
looking at it. That should look like a
completely normal quarter. And you know
why? Cuz it is a normal quarter. Uh but,
you've essentially added something to
it, right? And so, um I think it looks
good. Now, you can't show fully the back
side of it,
but you can show the front side of it.
And here is
the coin that was sent to me.
And in reality, no one's ever going to
notice the difference between what you
switched in and switched out and which
one is the uh original coin and which
one's the gimmick coin. Um so, this is
beautiful, I think. And they have done a
great job with this aspect.
I won't spend a lot more time on it
other than to say this method with this
improvement gimmick
consumable is really good, but I do have
one major problem with it that I'll chat
about a little bit later.
All right, so gimmick good.
Um
I I think it's nice about it is that
this gimmick allows you to show the pen
once penetrated from both sides. That's
one of the advancements here.
And I've seen online that people have
complained about once you've done the
penetration that it kind of
you can sort of start to detect what the
method is. That's not my experience at
all. In fact, to me it looks like, "Oh,
wow, that looks the way if you actually
melted it's uh
a pen through it, what it would look
like from the back end. Now, in reality,
most of us are going to just briefly be
showing the uh pen and from the back
side of people aren't going to be
staring at it in detail. So, I think
that's a little bit of magician thinking
uh on that, but um
that's my experience.
And with that said, let me add
I'll probably take away from everything
that I just said. Uh I think I've
probably put a demo at the front of this
and maybe I'll put bloopers at the end.
I did perform this for my son who knows
a lot of magic cuz he sees me perform
magic. And he immediately
uh said, "Oh,
well, that kind of looks like paper."
And uh he was able to discern the method
right away.
So, I I don't want to post that because
it sort of reveals method, but um
he he was able to figure it out right
away. I think for most muggles, they're
not going to notice and it's not a big
deal. That's my perception. Despite that
my experience was the opposite uh of
that. All right. So, once you run out of
your 100 consumables, you'll need to buy
more. If you want to buy 100 additional
consumables, they're $19.95.
Now, I think that's too expensive for
what it is. I think $10 would be a much
more appropriate price. I don't know how
much it costs them to make these, but um
$20 seems a little bit expensive to me.
But, and maybe I'm pissed still at the
tutorial being so bad, so I don't want
to say anything nice about it. But, it
does seem a little bit expensive for the
consumer. I will add, today I went to go
see the consumables and confirm what the
price is. Sold out.
long am I going to wait for them to uh
restock these? Uh will they restock
these? I'd like to assume that of course
they will. But, um found it a bit
annoying
uh on that. I will add, despite my rage
and being pissed off with this release,
I'm
going to perform this. I'm going to get
my 100 performances um out of the way.
And if I like it and getting good
good response,
yeah, I'll probably pay the $19.95
for the consumable. Um
probably somewhat reluctantly
cuz I cannot produce them myself. These
are something that are unique and not so
like, oh I can figure out my own way of
producing those. No, that's not going to
happen.
Um I'm not aware of anybody else making
this consumable. So, um
my thoughts on that for you. Do what you
will with it.
What's the skill level? Is it beginner
level? This is a beginner skill level
that is an effect that's performed by
professionals all the time. Um if you
are a beginner,
just understand that you purchased this,
the tutorial is inadequate. You can
take your time and figure it out, uh
which I believe you can. It'll be nice
to maybe have a mentor or or somebody
who's more experienced who can help you
through uh the switches. Um you can use
any switch you want with this.
The ones they teach I think are good
switches to use for this specific set of
conditions, uh but they're taught so
poorly.
It does require a little bit of practice
and spend time in the mirror. Uh the
upside of this is that being such a poor
tutorial, I found myself practicing a
what felt to me a more natural way of
how would I pull a coin off of um off of
a pen if it was penetration like this.
None of them taught on the video. And I
don't really want to have what feels
like this is how somebody would normally
pull it off. There's it's almost
backwards. It works for the tutorial. I
think it's fine method-wise. Uh
but
the upside is like, "Oh, I don't like
it. I'm going to figure out a way to do
a switch that really works for me. That
looks as clean as uh what is taught on
the tutorial." So, that could kind of be
considered an uh an upside.
All right, let me sort of um talk about
some of the um Oh, I should mention in
terms of skill level and stuff. The
downside of this um on the tutorial is
um it's
you just need to know how to do a slide
to slide is a
uh is a switch a coin switch. You use it
whatever you want. But, they never
talked about the ditch. And that like at
the end you might want to ditch the coin
to be completely free. They don't even
mention ditching the coin in this. Now,
in my humble opinion, I haven't
performed it thousands of times. Nine
out of 10 times I I just don't ditch cuz
no need to because people aren't
suspecting that I'm holding something
cuz it's been performed so cleanly.
However,
it would be nice for it to be at least
addressed. It's not even mentioned in
the tutorial. Again, just a major
major fail.
Let me go on about that one more time.
In this day and age,
the cheapest part of this production is
the tutorial. The consumables, the
production of the gas coin, that
actually costs money. That's probably
the most expensive portion of this.
Filming the tutorial is the cheapest
part of this. And that's the part that
they couldn't get right. Um all right.
Enough of that. Uh let's see, pros and
cons. Um
mention the tutorial.
The consumables are great.
Not great for a walk-around gig. If
you're doing working professionally
doing walk-around, the reset, you can't
reset in front of your spectator. You
need to step away and do the reset. So,
I think it's a one-and-done type of
effect. But, it's a good one-and-done
effect.
I think who's going to like this? I
think somebody who's an experienced
magician who likes everyday carry with
coin magic
with everyday objects. I think that's
who's who's going to going to like this
with great visual effects. And also the
fact that you can hand them out at the
end, and everyone can touch everything,
and there's nothing for them to see at
the end. So, let's talk about cost. So,
the cost of this is $39.95.
I actually think that's a very good
price point for this product. For as
good as an effect as it is,
I think that's a great price point.
Except for if you're new and you need a
good tutorial, it's a waste of time.
I do have a problem with the refills
costing $19.95. Essentially, 20 US
dollars for the refills. I think that's
overpriced. Should be half of that.
All right, that's it. That's my thought
on this. Uh it's disappointing for me
for an effect I love by a legend I
admire uh with just a
shitty
I mean, uh a terrible tutorial. And um
it really misses the mark, and I think
Penguin Magic's primary audience are
hobbyists and beginners. That's their
core audience. And they have
disrespected their core audience on this
one by not providing an adequate
tutorial.
It feels disrespectful to me.
If I were If you're brand new and you're
considering this, don't buy it because
Penguin should not be rewarded for
putting out
a sloppy tutorial. The effect is great.
What the materials provided are great.
Tutorial needs to be redone and taught.
And Eric Tate,
you're probably the person who's
responsible for this. And as much as I
great admiration
for
what you do in the work and I think it's
really
most of time excellent.
Um the tutorials needs to be better.
Take the time for somebody who's brand
new and make sure that they walk away.
Maybe you include somebody who's brand
new in magic and you do it
teach them in front of us the spectator
so that um
it
meets that mark. All right.
That's it for me. If you purchased this
and you hear my rant add your thoughts.
Maybe I'm totally wrong. Maybe you have
a different perspective. Think about if
you were brand new
uh person in magic, would this tutorial
be adequate for you or not?
Tell me about what the pain points are
for this in terms of things that you
like or dislike.
Um and uh tell me if I'm crazy or not.
All right, that's it. I really
appreciate every one of you guys being
here. By the way, if any of you are
going to uh Magic Live this year, I will
be there.
Please come up and say hello to me. I
would love to meet you. Uh would love to
say hi and shake your hand personally
and say thank you for watching the
channel. Do not be afraid. Please come
say hello. I am incredibly uh
approachable and would love to meet
people who like the channel. All right,
thank you everyone for being here. Make
sure that you hit that like button and
subscribe if you haven't yet subscribed.
I'm Fiddlin' Johnny and remember
keep fiddling around with magic.
I'll see you all next time. Bye-bye.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Mhm.
Mhm.